[
    {
        "name": "Food & Drink",
        "id": "food",
        "theme": "green",
        "quizzes": [
            {
                "type": "four-quarter",
                "question": "Name the Italian, semi-soft, rich cheese with blue veins through it.",
                "options": [
                    "Ricotta",
                    "Blue Cheese",
                    "Gorgonzola",
                    "Parmesan"
                ],
                "answer": [2]
            },
            {
                "type": "true-false",
                "question": "Coffee beans contain more caffeine than tea leaves.",
                "answer": false
            },
            {
                "type": "multi-select",
                "question": "What are the three ingredients in mead (spices excluded)?",
                "options": [
                    "Sugar",
                    "Honey",
                    "Cinnamon",
                    "Water",
                    "Brown Sugar",
                    "Yeast",
                    "Salt"
                ],
                "answer": [1,3,5]
            },
            {
                "type": "four-quarter",
                "question": "What crop does the Colorado Beetle attack?",
                "options": [
                    "Corn",
                    "Garlic",
                    "Potato",
                    "Wheat"
                ],
                "answer": [2]
            },
            {
                "type": "single-select-item",
                "question": "What vegetable did Mark Twain describe as “cabbage with a college education”?",
                "options": [
                    "Spinach",
                    "Broccoli",
                    "Cauliflower",
                    "Kale"
                ],
                "answer": [2]
            },
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "What name is given to a sugar syrup which is gently heated until it browns?",
                "answer": "Caramel"
            },
            {
                "type": "single-select",
                "question": "In Which city was chop suey invented?",
                "options": [
                    "Hong Kong",
                    "Taipei",
                    "New York",
                    "San Francisco"
                ],
                "answer": [3]
            },
            {
                "type": "picker",
                "question": "One of the fattiest fishes is salmon. 4 ounces contains how many grams of fat?",
                "min": 1,
                "max": 10,
                "answer": 9
            },
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "In which American State did chili con carne originate?",
                "answer": "Texas"
            },
            {
                "type": "four-quarter",
                "question": "What is the correct name for a cluster or bunch of bananas?",
                "options": [
                    "Foot",
                    "Hand",
                    "Flock",
                    "Pod"
                ],
                "answer": [1]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "name": "General Knowledge",
        "id": "knowledge",
        "theme": "yellow",
        "quizzes": [
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "Mole is a popular paste in Mexico. Mole is a mixture of chili’s and what other tasty ingredient?",
                "answer": "Chocolate"
            },
            {
                "type": "four-quarter",
                "question": "What is the name of the famous art deco skyscraper in New York City?",
                "options": [
                    "Trump Tower",
                    "Chrysler building",
                    "Empire State Building",
                    "The New York Times Building"
                ],
                "answer": [1]
            },
            {
                "type": "multi-select",
                "question": "Select the names of “The Three Musketeers”.",
                "options": [
                    "Chevy",
                    "Topeka",
                    "Athos",
                    "Duke",
                    "Porthos",
                    "John Felton",
                    "Aramis"
                ],
                "answer": [2,4,6]
            },
            {
                "type": "toggle-translate",
                "question": "Which is the correct translation of Zorro?",
                "options": [
                    [
                        "Zorro",
                        "Dog"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Zorro",
                        "Sword"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Zorro",
                        "Fox"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Zorro",
                        "Coyote"
                    ]
                ],
                "answer": [2]
            },
            {
                "type": "single-select-item",
                "question": "Which 1971 film, known for its violence, was the first to use Dolby sound?",
                "options": [
                    "Straw Dogs",
                    "Dirty Harry",
                    "A Clockwork Orange",
                    "Play Misty for me"
                ],
                "answer": [2]
            },
            {
                "type": "picker",
                "question": "How many counters does a backgammon player have?",
                "min": 0,
                "max": 30,
                "answer": 15
            },
            {
                "type": "true-false",
                "question": "There is a patron saint of The Internet.",
                "answer": true
            },
            {
                "type": "alpha-picker",
                "question": " Which letter other than X scores 8 in Scrabble?",
                "answer": "J"
            },
            {
                "type": "four-quarter",
                "question": "Four of the worst ten maritime disasters all took place in 1945. In which sea were all four ships sunk?",
                "options": [
                    "Mediterranean sea",
                    "Baltic Sea",
                    "The Bermuda Triangle",
                    "Black Sea"
                ],
                "answer": [1]
            },
            {
                "type": "single-select",
                "question": "What nut is used to flavor marzipan?",
                "options": [
                    "Walnut",
                    "Almond",
                    "Cashew",
                    "Pistachio"
                ],
                "answer": [1]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "name": "History",
        "id": "history",
        "theme": "blue",
        "quizzes": [
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "The first words spoken on the moon by Buzz Aldrin were these:",
                "start": "Contact ",
                "answer": "Light"
            },
            {
                "type": "single-select-item",
                "question": "What U.S. President committed an unpardonable sin by kissing the Queen Mother on the lips?",
                "options": [
                    "George W. Bush",
                    "Jimmy Carter",
                    "Barack Obama",
                    "Lyndon B. Johnson",
                    "Ronald Reagan"
                ],
                "answer": [1]
            },
            {
                "type": "true-false",
                "question": "Cleopatra was Egyptian.",
                "answer": false
            },
            {
                "type": "true-false",
                "question": "The Rosetta Stone is the name of the limestone slab that became the key for deciphering ancient Egyptian hieroglyphics.",
                "answer": false
            },
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "Prior to 1664 New York was called:",
                "start": "New ",
                "answer": "Amsterdam"
            },
            {
                "type": "multi-select",
                "question": "What are the surnames of Bonnie and Clyde?",
                "options": [
                    "Parson",
                    "Parker",
                    "Patterson",
                    "Barlow",
                    "Barret",
                    "Barrow"
                ],
                "answer": [1,5]
            },
            {
                "type": "four-quarter",
                "question": "Joan of Arc, in the 15th century, was the first female promoted to this rank in the French army:",
                "options": [
                    "Lieutenant",
                    "Sergeant",
                    "General",
                    "Captain"
                ],
                "answer": [2]
            },
            {
                "type": "picker",
                "question": "In which year did William Shakespeare die?",
                "min": 1615,
                "max": 1635,
                "answer": 1616
            },
            {
                "type": "single-select",
                "question": "On which island was Napoleon born?",
                "options": [
                    "Sardinia",
                    "Corsica",
                    "Tahiti",
                    "Réunion",
                    "New Caledonia"
                ],
                "answer": [1]
            },
            {
                "type": "multi-select",
                "question": "Which states did the United States gain after the Mexican War?",
                "options": [
                    "Arizona",
                    "New Mexico",
                    "Louisiana",
                    "California",
                    "Nevada",
                    "Utah",
                    "Texas"
                ],
                "answer": [1,3,6]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "name": "Geography",
        "id": "geography",
        "theme": "red",
        "quizzes": [
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "Name the other state in the USA that starts with the letter A:",
                "start": "Alabama, Alaska, Arizona, and ",
                "answer": "Arkansas"
            },
            {
                "type": "toggle-translate",
                "question": "Select which landmark to American state pairings are correct:",
                "options": [
                    [
                        "Las Vegas",
                        "Arizona"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Death Valley",
                        "California"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Mount Rushmore",
                        "North Dakota"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Fort Knox",
                        "Kentucky"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Kennedy Space Center",
                        "Florida"
                    ]
                ],
                "answer": [1,3,4]
            },
            {
                "type": "true-false",
                "question": "A person born in Lombardy is Italian.",
                "answer": true
            },
            {
                "type": "picker",
                "question": "Approximately how many kilometers of coastline does the United Kingdom have?",
                "min": 2000,
                "max": 5000,
                "step": 500,
                "answer": 2500
            },
            {
                "type": "multi-select",
                "question": "Which three countries have fifty or more nuclear reactors?",
                "options": [
                    "USA",
                    "Russia",
                    "Canada",
                    "Brazil",
                    "France",
                    "Japan",
                    "China"
                ],
                "answer": [0,4,5]
            },
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "What country would you visit to see Casablanca?",
                "answer": "Morocco"
            },
            {
                "type": "single-select-item",
                "question": "In which city was the 1992 Olympics?",
                "options": [
                    "Atlanta",
                    "Barcelona",
                    "Seoul",
                    "Sydney"
                ],
                "answer": [1]
            },
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": " What food is named after a northern German city on the river Elbe?",
                "answer": "Hamburger"
            },
            {
                "type": "multi-select",
                "question": "Select two countries that are linked by the Brenner Pass:",
                "options": [
                    "Germany",
                    "Croatia",
                    "Austria",
                    "Switzerland",
                    "France",
                    "Italy",
                    "Czech Republic"
                ],
                "answer": [2,5]
            },
            {
                "type": "single-select",
                "question": "Where can you find the Pensacola Mountains?",
                "options": [
                    "Florida",
                    "Switzerland",
                    "Antarctica",
                    "Argentina"
                ],
                "answer": [2]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "name": "Science and Nature",
        "id": "science",
        "theme": "green",
        "quizzes": [
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "What is the layer of the earth underneath the crust called?",
                "answer": "Mantle"
            },
            {
                "type": "single-select-item",
                "question": "What is the only bird that can fly backwards?",
                "options": [
                    "Crow",
                    "Hummingbird",
                    "Pelican",
                    "Seagull",
                    "Albatross",
                    "Falcon",
                    "Sparrow"
                ],
                "answer": [1]
            },
            {
                "type": "four-quarter",
                "question": "What is the only cat in the world that can’t retract its claws?",
                "options": [
                    "Meerkat",
                    "Bobcat",
                    "Cheetah",
                    "Siamese"
                ],
                "answer": [2]
            },
            {
                "type": "toggle-translate",
                "question": "Which chemical symbols are incorrect?",
                "options": [
                    [
                        "Helium",
                        "He"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Tungsten",
                        "W"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Lithium",
                        "Lt"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Nickel",
                        "Ni"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Copper",
                        "C"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Zinc",
                        "Zn"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Cadmium",
                        "Cd"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Potassium",
                        "K"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Silicon",
                        "Sn"
                    ]
                ],
                "answer": [2,4,8]
            },
            {
                "type": "true-false",
                "question": "The vitreous humour is found in the human eye.",
                "answer": true
            },
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "What’s the third color of the rainbow?",
                "answer": "Yellow"
            },
            {
                "type": "picker",
                "question": "How many toes do most birds have?",
                "min": 2,
                "max": 12,
                "answer": 8
            },
            {
                "type": "picker",
                "question": "If the temperature in Centigrade is minus 40 degrees what is the temperature in Fahrenheit?",
                "min": -100,
                "max": 0,
                "step": 5,
                "answer": -40
            },
            {
                "type": "four-quarter",
                "question": "What sort of creature is a fluke?",
                "options": [
                    "Bird",
                    "Insect",
                    "Worm",
                    "Bear"
                ],
                "answer": [2]
            },
            {
                "type": "fill-two-blanks",
                "question": "What two metals together make brass?",
                "answer": [
                    "Copper",
                    "Zinc"
                ]
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "name": "TV & Movies",
        "id": "tvmovies",
        "theme": "purple",
        "quizzes": [
            {
                "type": "multi-select",
                "question": "Select the actors who played James Bond:",
                "options": [
                    "Sean Connery",
                    "Clive Owen",
                    "Timothy Dalton",
                    "David Niven",
                    "Clint Eastwood",
                    "Toby Stephens"
                ],
                "answer": [0,2,3,5]
            },
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "In which movie were Kevin Bacon, Bill Paxton, and Tom hanks on an aircraft?",
                "answer": "Apollo 13"
            },
            {
                "type": "four-quarter",
                "question": "In which famous sci-fi film did Robert Patrick play an assassin?",
                "options": [
                    "Blade Runner",
                    "Terminator 2",
                    "Watchmen",
                    "Forbidden Planet"
                ],
                "answer": [1]
            },
            {
                "type": "single-select",
                "question": "What was the name of Mork and Mindy’s child?",
                "options": [
                    "Micah",
                    "Morty",
                    "Mearth",
                    "Magnus"
                ],
                "answer": [2]
            },
            {
                "type": "picker",
                "question": "How old is Bart Simpson?",
                "min": 6,
                "max": 13,
                "answer": 10
            },
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "Where had King Kong lived before coming to New York in the 1933 film \"King Kong\"?",
                "end": "island",
                "answer": "skull"
            },
            {
                "type": "true-false",
                "question": "Stanley Kubrick directed the 1971 film \"THX 1138.\"",
                "answer": false
            },
            {
                "type": "picker",
                "question": "The film \"Ben Hur\" holds the record for winning more Oscars than any other movie. How many?",
                "min": 4,
                "max": 15,
                "answer": 11
            },
            {
                "type": "four-quarter",
                "question": "Which Spielberg film gives an unflattering account of Carcharodon Carcharias?",
                "options": [
                    "Saving Private Ryan",
                    "E.T.",
                    "Jaws",
                    "The Color Purple"
                ],
                "answer": [2]
            },
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "In which film did Robert De Niro ask “Are you talkin’ to me?”",
                "answer": "Taxi Driver"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "name": "Music",
        "id": "music",
        "theme": "blue",
        "quizzes": [
            {
                "type": "four-quarter",
                "question": "Who was the youngest Beatle?",
                "options": [
                    "John",
                    "Paul",
                    "George",
                    "Ringo"
                ],
                "answer": [2]
            },
            {
                "type": "multi-select",
                "question": "Best known for playing the trumpet:",
                "options": [
                    "Miles Davis",
                    "Chet Baker",
                    "Art Farmer",
                    "John Coltrane",
                    "Dizzy Gillespie",
                    "Freddie Hubbard"
                ],
                "answer": [0,1,2,4,5]
            },
            {
                "type": "toggle-translate",
                "question": "Which nationality of the following composers is incorrect?",
                "options": [
                    [
                        "Johann Sebastian Bach",
                        "German"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Sergei Rachmaninov",
                        "Czechoslovakian"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Frederic Chopin",
                        "Polish"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Giacoma Puccini",
                        "Italian"
                    ],
                    [
                        "George Gershwin",
                        "Austrian"
                    ]
                ],
                "answer": [1,4]
            },
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "Prior to forming BAD which group did Mick Jones Belong to?",
                "answer": "The Clash"
            },
            {
                "type": "single-select-item",
                "question": "Frank Sinatra covered this song made famous by a popular Jim Henson character.",
                "options": [
                    "Welcome to Sesame Street",
                    "It’s not Easy Bein’ Green",
                    "Hugga Wugga",
                    "Wild Thing"
                ],
                "answer": [1]
            },
            {
                "type": "true-false",
                "question": "Queen’s Bohemian Rhapsody was a Christmas number one hit in the UK, twice.",
                "answer": true
            },
            {
                "type": "picker",
                "question": "How many symphonies did Beethoven write?",
                "min": 1,
                "max": 16,
                "answer": 9
            },
            {
                "type": "single-select",
                "question": "Which was the first Beach Boys number one song in the US?",
                "options": [
                    "Kokomo",
                    "Help Me",
                    "Rhonda",
                    "I Get Around",
                    "Good Vibrations"
                ],
                "answer": [3]
            },
            {
                "type": "four-quarter",
                "question": "Noah Benjamin Lenox is an experimental musician better known as which animal?",
                "options": [
                    "Grizzly Bear",
                    "Panda Bear",
                    "Gorrilla",
                    "Pitbull"
                ],
                "answer": [1]
            },
            {
                "type": "single-select-item",
                "question": "After Simeon Oliver Coxe III incorporated a 1940s audio oscillator his band was renamed this, after a William Butler Yeats poem:",
                "options": [
                    "Silver Apples",
                    "Golden Oranges",
                    "White Rose",
                    "Black Moth"
                ],
                "answer": [0]
            }
        ]
    },    {
        "name": "Entertainment",
        "id": "entertainment",
        "theme": "red",
        "quizzes": [
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "Where was superman born?",
                "answer": "Krypton"
            },
            {
                "type": "four-quarter",
                "question": "What catchphrase is associated with the Daleks from Doctor Who?",
                "options": [
                    "Eradicate",
                    "Exterminate",
                    "Eliminate",
                    "Execute"
                ],
                "answer": [1]
            },
            {
                "type": "picker",
                "question": "In the film Cool Hand Luke, how many hard boiled eggs did Paul Newman eat to win a bet?",
                "min": 20,
                "max": 80,
                "answer": 50
            },
            {
                "type": "true-false",
                "question": "Frank Sinatra paid a $240,000 ransom to free his kidnapped son.",
                "answer": true
            },
            {
                "type": "multi-select",
                "question": "Which two British actors have played Obi Wan Kenobi in the Star Wars films?",
                "options": [
                    "Sir Alec Guinness",
                    "David Prowse",
                    "James Earl Jones",
                    "Harrison Ford",
                    "Ewan McGregor",
                    "Anthony Daniels"
                ],
                "answer": [0,4]
            },
            {
                "type": "picker",
                "question": "How many Oscars were won by the film Matrix at the 2000 Academy Awards ceremony?",
                "min": 0,
                "max": 11,
                "answer": 4
            },
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "Late American artist Andy Warhol observed:",
                "start": "“Two people kissing always looks like ",
                "end": ".”",
                "answer": "Fish"
            },
            {
                "type": "single-select",
                "question": "Who played Dr. John Hammond in Jurassic Park?",
                "options": [
                    "Anthony Hopkins",
                    "Jeff Goldblum",
                    "Richard Attenborough",
                    "Emmet Brown"
                ],
                "answer": [2]
            },
            {
                "type": "picker",
                "question": "What year did the Live Aid concerts take place?",
                "min": 1965,
                "max": 1990,
                "answer": 1985
            },
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "What is Mr. Burns’ first name?",
                "answer": "Charles"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "name": "Sports",
        "id": "sports",
        "theme": "purple",
        "quizzes": [
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "What is the national sport of Canada?",
                "answer": "Lacrosse"
            },
            {
                "type": "four-quarter",
                "question": "Which country won every Olympic Men’s hockey gold medal from 1928 to 1956?",
                "options": [
                    "Canada",
                    "Russia",
                    "India",
                    "USA"
                ],
                "answer": [2]
            },
            {
                "type": "true-false",
                "question": "A biathlon event consists of running a half marathon and biking 56 miles.",
                "answer": false
            },
            {
                "type": "picker",
                "question": "How many players are in a game of water polo?",
                "min": 10,
                "max": 25,
                "answer": 14
            },
            {
                "type": "toggle-translate",
                "question": "Which sports and team names are incorrectly associated?",
                "options": [
                    [
                        "Cleveland Indians",
                        "Baseball"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Leicester Tigers",
                        "Rugby Union"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Bradford Bulls",
                        "Hockey"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Belle Vue Aces",
                        "Poker"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Wigan Wasps",
                        "Lacrosse"
                    ],
                    [
                        "Kent Spitfires",
                        "Cricket"
                    ]
                ],
                "answer": [2,3,4]
            },
            {
                "type": "multi-select",
                "question": "Which cities have hosted the Olympic games?",
                "options": [
                    "Athens",
                    "Lake Placid",
                    "Innsbruck",
                    "New York",
                    "Capetown",
                    "St. Mortiz"
                ],
                "answer": [0,1,2,4,5]
            },
            {
                "type": "four-quarter",
                "question": "Which American was the best paid sportsman in 1920?",
                "options": [
                    "Jack Dempsey",
                    "Babe Ruth",
                    "Big Bill Tilden",
                    "Bobby Jones"
                ],
                "answer": [1]
            },
            {
                "type": "single-select-item",
                "question": " What do you call a stadium used for cycling events?",
                "options": [
                    "Cycleplex",
                    "Velodrome",
                    "Pumptrack",
                    "Speedway"
                ],
                "answer": [1]
            },
            {
                "type": "fill-blank",
                "question": "In 1954, Joe Di Maggio married Norma Jean Baker who was also known as?",
                "answer": "Marilyn Monroe"
            },
            {
                "type": "picker",
                "question": "About how many kilometers are in a marathon?",
                "min": 10,
                "max": 65,
                "answer": 42
            }
        ]
    }
]
